Cruiser Houston Collection, 1917-2003
University of Houston Libraries
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1917-2003
  - Individuals
    - Walter B. Woodson, [ca. 1934-1935]. (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Memorials
    - Commemoration service, USS McCluskey, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Presentation of painting, 50th Anniversary of Battle of Sunda Strait, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - USS Houston (CA-30) monument, undated. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - USS Houston (CA 30) plaque, Admiral Nimitz National Museum of the Pacific War, Fredericksburg, Texas, 1981. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Houston Volunteers monument dedication, William A. Bernrieder and Mrs. William Glassford, 1974. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Houston Volunteers monument, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Manila American Cemetery & Memorial, Philippines, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific (“Punchbowl”), Honolulu, undated. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific (“Punchbowl”) plaque, Honolulu, undated. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - National Memorial Cemetery of the Pacific (“Punchbowl”), Honolulu. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Plaque, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Rooks, Albert H. plaque, Admiral Nimitz National Museum of the Pacific War, Fredericksburg, Texas, 1981. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Wreath laying ceremony, Brisbane, Australia, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Wreath laying ceremony, Sunda Strait, 1981. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Wreath laying ceremony, Sunda Strait, 1981. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Model, USS Houston (CA-30)
    - Model Presentation, USS Houston (CA 30), 1958. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Model, USS Houston (CA 30), 1981. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Model, USS Houston (CA 30), 1981. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Other
    - Formal surrender of Japan, September 2, 1945. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Iloilo and Olongapo, Philippine Islands, 1941. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Newport News Shipyard, 1928. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Porthole, 1992. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - POW Experience
    - Burma-Thai railway and POW camp, [1942-1945]. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Burma-Thai railway and POW camp, [1942-1945]. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Burma-Thai railway, POWs working on, and POW camp, [1942-1945]. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Evacuation of POWs, Rat Buri, Thailand, [1945]. (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Donor: Eugene Wilkinson
    - Evacuation of POWs, Rat Buri, Thailand, [1945]. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Evacuation of POWs, Rat Buri, Thailand, [1945]. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Evacuation of POWs, Rat Buri, Thailand, [1945]. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Evacuation of POWs, USS Chenango, Nagasaki, Japan, 1945. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Evacuation of POWs, [1945]. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Evacuation of POWs, [1945]. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Japanese soldiers, Ohasi, Japan, 1945. (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Donor: Henry P. Thew (in exhibit)
    - Harold McManus, Harry Stone, and Colonel Suga, [ca. 1945] (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - POW in mine repair shop, Ohasi, Japan, 1943. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - POW camp, Ohasi, Japan, August 1945. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - POWs, Ohasi, Japan, August 1945. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - POWs, October 1945. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - POWs, [1945]. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Silver Service
    - Silver service, undated. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Silver service, undated. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Silver service. Walter E. Monteith and William A. Bernrieder, [1930?]. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Ships, Other
    - Cleveland class cruiser, [copy print, National Archives], undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - HMAS Perth, undated (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - HMAS Perth, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - HM de Ruyter, undated. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - HM de Ruyter, undated. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - HM Evertsen, undated. (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - HM Java, undated. (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - HM Kortenaer, undated. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - HM Witte de With, undated. (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - USS Louisville (CA 28), [copy print, National Archives], undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - USS Miami (CL 89), [copy print, U.S. Naval Photographic Center], 1944 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Special Occasions
    - Christmas, 1935. (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Christmas, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Christmas, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Christmas, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Christmas, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Christmas, 1936. (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Christmas piano, 1936. (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Farewell Dance, June 11, 1937. (Box 54, Folder 14)
      Donor: Fred Viskovich
    - Houston Ball, The Canidrome, Shanghai, [1930]. (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Sports Activities
    - Baseball team, 1940 1941. (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Boxing, Frank L.H. Pistole, undated. (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Boxing, Frank L.H. Pistole, undated. (Box 3, Folder 63)
- NEGATIVES AND SLIDES, 1927-2002
  This series includes a variety of negatives and slides, as well as digital copies of all negatives. The negatives are in a variety of formats and sizes. Most of the negatives in this series were donated by Otto Schwarz and the USS Houston Survivors Association, and many of them are copy negatives of other images.
  Box 4 contains CD-ROMs of digital images that were created by Special Collections staff to provide better access to the negatives. Patrons visiting the reading room in person may view the CD-ROMs on a laptop or at a computer workstation in our reading room. A printed list of the contents of the negatives is also available. The negatives were scanned at their original size in order to serve as a positive image contact sheet for easier browsing. Because the digital images on the CD-ROM are so small, patrons wishing to order reproductions of are recommended to have their print, slide, or photograph made directly from the original negative. Unfortunately, we cannot make these images available in digital format to people who are not visiting the reading room in person.
  - Digital images scanned from Cruiser Houston Collection negatives, CD-ROMs, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Digital images scanned from Cruiser Houston Collection negatives, printed list, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Lecture slides, Otto Schwarz, undated. (Box 5, Binder Binder)
  - Lecture slides key, Otto Schwarz, undated. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Negatives and slides of flag made in POW camp, 2002. (Box 5, Binder Binder)
    Donor: Beryl Striewski
  - Negatives: Honolulu, 1939-1940. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Donor: Vivian Barber
  - Negatives: Honolulu, 1939-1940. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Negatives: USS Houston (CA-30), 1939-1940. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Negatives, various, from UH Libraries and USS Houston Survivors Association (Box 5, Folder 5-36)
  - Negatives, various, from Otto Schwarz. Donor: Otto Schwarz (Box 6)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1932-2000
  Correspondence is divided into four sub-series by format: Postcards from POW Camp, Telegrams, Letters, and Envelopes. The Postcards from POW Camp series includes postcards written by Houston crew members while they were being held as prisoners-of-war. These postcards were highly censored by the Japanese military. The Postcards from POW Camp, Telegrams, and Envelopes sub-series are each arranged by sender. If there are multiple items from the same sender, they are further arranged by receiver. If there are multiple items from the same sender to the same receiver, they are further arranged by date.
  The Letters sub-series is organized somewhat differently. It contains several large groups of letters that all pertain to one individual or family: William C. Batchelor, Jr., Henry Nickel, Claude E. Parker, Frank Pistole, William Slough, and the family of Francis B. Weiler. These groups of letters are arranged separately from the rest. Each group is arranged by sender, then by receiver, and then by date. The rest of the letters fall under the General heading, where they are arranged by sender, then by receiver, and then by date.
  The letters of the family of Francis B. Weiler are photocopies of materials in the collection of the Naval Museum, U.S. Naval Academy.
  - Postcards from POW Camp
    - (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Bill Batchelor, [Jr.] to W.C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Moulmein, Burma, [ca. 1942-1943].
      - Leroy Alvin Buckner to Roy Noble Buckner, Thailand, February 20, 1945.
        Donor: Leroy Buckner
      - Leroy Alvin Buckner to R.N. Buckner, Siagon [sic], August 22, 1945.
      - George E. Detre to Mrs. C.J. Detre, Moulmein, Burma, [ca. 1942-1943].
      - Frank Dopson Ellis to Mrs. G.W. Vogan, Nike, Thailand, [ca. 1942-1945].
      - Frank D. Ellis to Mr. J.W. Vogan, Moulmein, Burma, [ca. 1942-1943].
      - Henry Nickel to Mrs. J. Nickel, Moulmein, Burma, [ca. 1942-1943].
      - Henry Nickel to Mrs. J. Nickel, Nike, Thailand, [ca. 1942-1945].
      - C. Eugene Parker to Mrs. A.S. Murphy, Thailand, March 3, 1944.
        Donor: Claude E. Parker
      - Claude Eugene Parker to Mrs. A.S. Murphy, Thailand, [ca. 1942-1945].
      - Claude E. Parker to Mrs. A.S. Murphy, Nike, Thailand, [ca. 1942-1945].
      - Frank L.H. Pistole to Mrs. Lawrence W. Pistole, Moulmein, Burma, [ca. 1942-1943].
      - William Ross, Jr. to Mrs. Harry Olson, Oct. 18-19, 1943.
        Donor: William Ross, Jr.
      - William Ross, Jr. to Mrs. Harry Olsen, Thailand, May 19, 1944, postmarked Feb. 6, 1945.
      - John Stefanek to Mrs. Lewis Stefanek, Nike, Thailand, [ca. 1942-1945].
  - Telegrams
    - (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Louis Denfeld to Imogene Thew, Washington D.C., October 8, 1945
        with two envelopes.
      - Randall Jacobs to Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., March 14, 1942.
        Donor: Betty Batchelor
      - Randall Jacobs to Mrs. Ora Magelene Ellis, Washington D.C., August 31, 1945.
      - Randall Jacobs to Mr. and Mrs. A. Kondzela, Washington D.C., August 30, 1945
      - Randall Jacobs to Emma Carolyne Pistole, Washington D.C., March 14, 1942.
      - Randall Jacobs to Emma C. Pistole, Washington D.C., [ca. 1944-1945].
      - Randall Jacobs to Imogene Thew, Washington D.C., March 14, 1942
      - Randall Jacobs to George Edwin White, Washington D.C., March 1, 1942
        (photocopy).
        Donor: Charles E. White
      - Navy Department to William Charles Batchelor, [Sr.], BUNAV [Bureau of Navigation], March 15, 1942.
      - [Nettke?] to Mrs. Frank D. Ellis, San Bruno, California, May 14, 1944.
      - OPNAV to Navy Yard, Cavite; Navy Yard, Puget Sound; Houston, [1940].
      - Samuel G. O’Regan to Mrs. Frank D. Ellis, Oakland, California, May 3, 1948
        with envelope.
      - Henry Prior Thew to Henry Wm. Thew, Washington D.C., June 16, [1942-1945]
      - Colonel Williamson to Mrs. William C. Batchelor, Fort Myer, Vir[ginia], May 28, 1948.
  - Letters
    - William C. Batchelor, Jr. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - H. B. Atkinson to William C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., July 3, 1945.
      - H. B. Atkinson to Mr. and Mrs. William Batchelor Sr., Washington D.C., August 27, 1945
        with document.
      - H. B. Atkinson to Lt. & Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., September 6, 1945
      - H. B. Atkinson to Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., March 8, 1946.
      - F. Byrne Austin to Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., February 28, 1951.
      - Frank W. Barton to Annabelle K. Batchelor, Washington D.C., September 18, 1951.
      - Frank W. Barton to Annabelle K. Batchelor, Washington D.C., February 2, 1953
      - Betty Batchelor to Navy Awards Board, La Connor, Washington, [ca. 1985], (photocopy). With letter from C.R. McDonnold, St. Louis, MO, June 13, 1985, document, and clipping (photocopies).
      - William Charles Batchelor, Jr. to Mother [Annabelle K. Batchelor], December 30, 1941
      - W.C. Batchelor [Sr.] to Chief of the Bureau of Navigation, March 19, 1940.
      - W.C. Batchelor, [Sr.] to Joe Fagen, Pearl Harbor, T.H., January 26, 1943.
      - William C. Batchelor, [Sr.] to The Chief of the Bureau of Personnel, January 5, 1944.
      - W.C. Batchelor, [Sr.] to The Prisoner of War Information Bureau, January 30, 1944.
      - W.C. Batchelor, [Sr.] to Circulation Manager, Time Magazine, Shelton, Washington, March 22, 1944.
      - W.C. Batchelor, [Sr.] to Headmaster, Fort Union Military Academy, Shelton, Washington, [ca. 1944].
      - W.C. Batchelor to The Director, U.S. Veterans Administration, Insurance Division, Keyport, Washington, September 7, 1945.
      - Howard E. Brooks to To Whom it May Concern, March 21, 1998.
      - Carl N. Burgard to To Whom it May Concern, Aloha, Oregon, February 22, 1998. With letter to Betty Miles, Aloha, Oregon, February 22, 1998.
      - Edwin J. Carpenter to W.C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., February 24, 1944.
      - David Clark to Betty Batchelor, Victoria, Australia, April 28, 1989
        with drawing of 80 Kilo Camp.
      - C.M. Drury to Dr. William B. Pugh, Washington D.C., April 26, 1946.
      - J. L. Fitzgerald to Betty Batchelor, Victoria, Australia, September 21, 1989.
      - James Forrestal to William C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., July 23, 1945.
      - James Forrestal to Mrs. William C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., July 23, 1945.
      - Harold S. Hamlin Jr. to Lt. and Mrs. Batchelor, Washington D.C., October 23, 1945.
      - W.J. McNicol, Jr. to William C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., June 25, 1945.
      - A.C. Jacobs to Mr. and Mrs. William C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., January 10, 1944.
      - A.C. Jacobs to William C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., January 28, 1944.
      - A.C. Jacobs to Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., February 5, 1944.
      - Randall Jacobs to William C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., February 10, 1940.
      - Randall Jacobs to William C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., March 10, 1943.
      - Randall Jacobs to Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., March 10, 1943.
      - Christopher J. Kersting to William Charles Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., June 21, 1950.
        With Presidential Unit Citation.
      - Al Kopp to To Whom It May Concern, [Minnesota], February 21, 1998. With letter to Mrs. Miles, February 25, 1998.
      - C.R. McDonnold to Betty Batchelor, St. Louis, Missouri, June 13, 1985.
      - Herbert B. Maw to Annabelle K. Batchelor, Salt Lake City, Utah, May 14, 1946.
      - M.J. Mayer to Otto Schwarz, March 6, 1991.
      - Ross T. McIntire to Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., August 19, 1946.
      - David Milne to Betty A. Miles, Victoria, Australia, September 23, 1988
      - C.W. Nimitz to William C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., March 16, 1940.
      - C.W. Nimitz to William C. Batchelor, Jr., Washington D.C., May 17, 1940.
      - M.E. Reeder to Mr. & Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., February 17, 1950.
      - M.E. Reeder to William C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., May 12, 1950
        with report of casualty.
      - M.E. Reeder to William C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., June 29, 1950
      - Jack D. Smith to To Whom it May Concern, Chula Vista, California, with letter To Whom It May Concern, Chula Vista, California, Feb. 20, 1998.
      - A.E. Stone to William C. Batchelor, [Sr.], Washington D.C., July 7, 1945.
      - C.A. Swanson to Mrs. W.C. Batchelor, Washington D.C., September 17, 1947.
      - O.N. Thomas to Annabelle K. Batchelor, Olympia, Washington, October 30, 1950.
      - Max W. Wilker to To Whom it May Concern, February 21, 1998.
      - George H. Williams, Washington D.C., April 10, 1946.
    - Henry Nickel (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - F.E. [Kenfeld?] to Henry Nickel, Washington D.C., September 28, 1945.
      - Margaret Uhrich to Henry Nickel, Dinuba, California, January 19, 1944
      - Margaret Uhrich to Henry Nickel, Dinuba, California, February 17, 1944
      - Margaret Uhrich to Henry Nickel, Dinuba, California, March 13, 1944
      - Margaret Uhrich to Henry Nickel, Dinuba, California, March 28, 1944
      - Marie to Henry Nickel, San Francisco, California, January 10, 1944.
      - Mr. & Mrs. J. Nickel to Henry Nickel, Dinuba, California, February 17, 1944
      - Mrs. [L.D.?] “Eppie” Williams to Henry Nickel, Burlingame, California, January 9, 1944
      - Mrs. J. Nickel to Henry Nickel, Dinuba, California, January 11, 1944
      - Mrs. J. Nickel to Henry Nickel, Dinuba, California, March 27, 1944
    - Claude E. Parker (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Agnes and [Forrest] “Dunk” [Duncan] to [Claude] Gene [Parker], Atchison, Kansas, January 26, 1942
      - Mr. & Mrs. A.S. Murphy to Claude E. Parker, Lawrence, Kansas, December 12, 1944.
      - Mr. & Mrs. A.S. Murphy to Claude Eugene Parker, Lawrence, Kansas, February 16, 1945.
      - Mr. & Mrs. A.S. Murphy to Claude Eugene Parker, Lawrence, Kansas, May 29, 1945.
      - Mr. & Mrs. A.S. Murphy to Claude E. Parker, Lawrence, Kansas, June 28, 1945.
      - Mr. & Mrs. A.S. Murphy to Claude Eugene Parker, Lawrence, Kansas, July 21, 1945.
      - Claude Eugene Parker to Mr. & Mrs. A.S. Murphy, Manila Bay, P.I., December 14, 1940
        with commemorative envelope.
      - [Claude] Gene [Parker] to Mr. & Mrs. A.S. Murphy, Olangapo, P.I., January 12-13, 1941
      - [Claude] Gene [Parker] to Mr. & Mrs. Forrest Duncan, Manila Bay, February 17, 1941
      - [Claude] Gene [Parker] to Mr. & Mrs. Forrest Duncan, Manila Bay, May 13, 1941
      - [Claude] Gene [Parker], USS Houston Christmas card, Philippines.
    - Frank Pistole (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Sister M. Agnella to Mr. & Mrs. Pistole, Bloomington, Illinois, March 18, 1942.
      - Bill Baines to Mrs. Pistole, Japan, February 11, 1946.
      - C. Wayland Brooks to Emma Carolyn Pistole, Washington D.C., October 25, 1945. [with A.C. Jacobs letter on reverse]
      - H. Feldman to Emma C. Pistole, Washington D.C., April 22, 1949 [with Ross T. McIntire letter on reverse].
      - Harold S. Hamlin, Jr. to Mrs. Pistole, Washington D.C., October 23, 1945.
      - Merle Hobbs to Mr. & Mrs. Pistole, November 11, 1946.
      - A.C. Jacobs to Emma C. Pistole, Washington D.C., January 10, 1944. [with C. Wayland Brooks letter on reverse]
      - Ross T. McIntire to Emma Carolyn Pistole, Washington D.C., September 6, 1946 [with H. Feldman letter on reverse].
      - [Frank] “Butch” [Pistole] to C[larence] & Gladys, Manila, P.I. February 18, 1941.
      - [Frank] “Butch” [Pistole] to Aunt & Uncle, Manila, P.I. February 24, 1941.
      - Frank L.H. Pistole to Mother & Family, December 30, 1941.
      - Frank Pistole to Mother, USS Houston, February 10, 1942
      - Frank Pistole to Aunt & Uncle, February 14, 1942.
      - [Frank] “Butch” [Pistole] to [Mother?], USS Houston Christmas card, Philippines, [1941?].
    - William Slough (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Red Burke to O.E. Baer, November 16, 1934
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, San Diego, [California], May 27, 1934
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, San Diego, [California], June 2, 1934
      - Wm. “Bill (Tex)” Slough to Martin A. “Bud” Slough, San Diego, California, June 7, 1934, with envelope
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, San Diego, [California], June 10, 1934
      - Bill (Tex) [Slough] to Moms, San Diego, [California], June 22, 1934
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, San Diego, [California], June 29, 1934
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, San Diego, California, July 2, 1934
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, July 1934
      - W.M. “Bill” Slough to O.E. Baer, San Diego Harbor, August 23, 1934, with envelope
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, October 10, 1934
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, San Pedro, California, November 10, 1934
      - Wm. “Bill” [Slough] to O.E. Baer, San Pedro, California, November 10, 1934, with envelope
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, Long Beach, California, November 26, 1934
      - Wm. “Bill” Slough to Mrs. D.W. “Moms” Slough, Mare Island, California, December 9, 1934, with envelope
      - [William] Tex [Slough] to Moms, Long Beach, California, January 6, 1935
      - Bill [Slough] to Mr. & Mrs. O.E. Baer, Long Beach, California, February 10, 1935, with envelope
      - Bill [Slough] to Mrs. O.E. “Moms” Baer, Long Beach, California, February 24, 1935, with envelope
      - Bill [Slough] to Mrs. O.E. Baer, Long Beach, California, March 3, 1935, with envelope
      - W.M. “Bill” Slough to Mr. & Mrs. O.E. Baer, Long Beach, California, March 24, 1935, with envelope
      - Bill [Slough] to Mrs. D.W. Baer, Long Beach, California, April 6, 1935, with envelope
      - Bill [Slough] to Mrs. D.W. “Madre Mio” Baer, Long Beach, California, April 13, 1935, with envelope
      - [William] Tex [Slough] to Mrs. O.E. “Moms” Baer, San Diego, [California], June 13, 1935, with envelope
      - William M. “Bill” Slough to Mr. & Mrs. O.E. Baer, Blaine, Washington, July 5, 1935, with envelope
      - William M. “Bill” Slough to Mrs. O.E. “Moms” Baer, At sea, July 12, 1935, with envelope
      - [William] Willyam (Tex) Nuts and Bolts [Slough] to Mother of Mine, Mare Island, California, February 14, 1936
      - Bill [Slough] to Moms, Long Beach, California, March 11, 1936
      - Clara & [Caraly?] to Honey, Tuesday [ca. 1935]
    - Francis B. Weiler, family of (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - F.W. Boehm to Mrs. George Weiler, Washington D.C., July 5, 1950 (photocopy)
      - Bureau of Naval Personnel, Navy Department, Service of Lt.(jg) Francis Brooks Weiler, September 13, 1945 (photocopy)
      - Gavin Campbell to Mrs. Weiler, Portland, Victoria, Australia, March 11, 1945 (photocopy)
      - Joseph C. Dalton to Mrs. [Payne?], Sparks, undated (photocopy)
      - Joseph C. Dalton to Mrs. Weiler, Sparks, MD, April 7, 1943, with Joseph C. Dalton to Gentlemen [Mr. England?], March 29, 1943, and J.F. Dalton to Mother and Dad [Mr. & Mrs. Joseph C. Dalton], Zentauji War Prison Camp, Japan, August 28, 1942 (all photocopies)
      - L.E. Denfeld to Dr. and Mrs. George S. Weiler, Washington D.C., November 16, 1944, with Presidential Unit Citation facsimile (photocopies)
      - Wade DeWeese to Rear Admiral James B. Weiler, June 22, 1961 (photocopy)
      - Betty Kirkpatrick to Mrs. Weiler, Ardmore, PA, December 3, 1942,, with poem, letter from William Glassford to Mr. Hamill, June 4, 1942, and letter from Mrs. John L. Stivers to Mrs. Kirkpatrick, [ca. 1942] (all photocopies)
      - J.R. Stimmel to George S. Weiler, Gardner, ND, March 1, 1943 (photocopy)
      - F[?] A. Todd to Dr. & Mrs. Weiler, Philadelphia, [PA], April 7 (photocopy)
    - General
      - American Ex-POWs, Santa Clara Valley Chapter, various, 1956-1958. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Ernest & Carolyn Arroyo to Otto Schwarz, Honolulu, Hawaii, Dec. 7, 1993. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - H. B. Atkinson to Howard Louis Chandler, Jr., Washington D.C., March 8, 1946 (photocopy). (Box 8, Folder 2)
        Donor: Dan T. Chandler
      - Wm. A. Bernrieder to the Editor of the Houston Chronicle, Houston, Texas, March 27, 1962, with The Cruiser Houston Story (photocopy). (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Wm. A. Bernrieder to Harold Rooks, September 29, 1982, with note to Otto Schwarz (photocopy). (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - E. A. Bush to Lieut. Barrett, late December 1943 (printed digital copy). (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - George Bush to USS Houston Survivors Association, Washington [D.C.], February 24, 1992. (Box 8, Folder 2)
        Donor: Val Roberts-Poss
      - George W. Bush to USS Houston Survivors Association, Austin, Texas, April 26, 1995,, with letter from Nikki Richnow to Evelyn Poss. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - George W. Bush to USS Houston Survivors Association, Austin, Texas, February 14, 2000. (Box 8, Folder 2)
        Donor: Lin Drees
      - Gavin Campbell to Otto Schwarz, Denistone, Australia, August 5, 1989. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Edwin J. Carpenter to Mrs. J.W. Vogan, Washington D.C., January 24, 1944. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Joe Davis to Mrs. Francis M. Davis and others; Great Lakes, Illinois; Pearl Harbor, T.H.; Manila, P.I.; July 6, 1940-March 24, 1942 (transcriptions in booklet with other photocopied material). (Box 8, Folder 3)
        Donor: Nancy Adams
      - Nick Day to Otto [Schwarz], May 25, 1981. (Box 8, Folder 4)